So I realized that day one of week one has been a pretty long day, and I assure you that the other,
첫째 주 첫날은 정말 긴 하루였어요 그리고 다음 날은 분명히
generally speaking, the other days won't be as long.
그렇게 길지 않을 거예요
We had some foundational work to do to get the environments up and running, and hopefully that you're
환경 구축과 실행을 위한 기초 작업이 있었어요 여러분이 만족하셨으면
happy that we've got there and you're feeling satisfied that we ran our first big project.
좋겠습니다 첫 번째 큰 프로젝트를 실행했다는 것에 대해서요
As a quick recap of what we got done at the very beginning, seems like an age ago we used to run LMS
초기에 했던 것을 짧게 요약해보죠 아주 오래 전에 LMS 오픈 소스 LMS를
open source LMS locally on your box, running them to generate content.
로컬로 실행했었어요 콘텐츠 생성을 위해서요
Then we set up the environment, and then we used open AI in the cloud to make a call to frontier models
환경을 설정하고 클라우드에서 오픈 인공지능을 사용해 GPT 4에 프런티어 모델을
to GPT four.
호출했죠
Mini was the model we used to generate text there, and obviously we're using here a closed source model
미니는 텍스트를 생성하기 위해 사용한 모델입니다. 우리는 비공개 소스 모델을 사용하고 있는데
that is maybe 1000 or 10,000 times larger.
1000 혹은 10,000배 정도 더 크죠.
We pay a small price for that in the form of a fraction of a cent, but we do have to to pay to use
우린 그걸 위해 1센트도 안 되는 작은 대가를 지불하지만 그걸 사용하려면 돈을 내야 하죠
that.
하지만 작은 국내산보다 품질이 훨씬 좋아요.
Um, we learned how to distinguish between a system prompt and a user prompt just at a high level.
높은 수준에서 시스템 프롬프트와 사용자 프롬프트를 구별하는 법을 배웠어요
We'll do a lot more on that, of course, in the coming days.
앞으로 며칠 동안 더 자세히 다룰 거예요
Uh, system prompt setting the tone, the context of the conversation, the user prompt, which is the
시스템 프롬프트에서 톤을 설정하고 대화의 맥락을 설정합니다 대화 자체가 사용자
conversation itself.
프롬프트죠
We used it for the opener.
오프닝으로 썼어요
Later, we'll be using it for many rounds of conversation.
나중에 이걸로 많은 대화를 나눌 거예요
And then most importantly, we applied this to the field of summarization and a critical use case that
그리고 가장 중요한 것은 요약과 주요 유스케이스에 적용한 것입니다.
comes up so many times it's applicable to many different problems.
많은 문제들에 적용할 수 있어요.
It's something that I hope you'll find ways to use this in your day job, in what you do already.
이걸 본업에서도 활용할 방법을 찾길 바라요 이미 하고 있는 일에서요
And if not, then certainly you should be able to find personal projects that you could come up with
그렇지 않다면 개인 프로젝트를 찾아 적용할 수
where you could apply this.
있어야 해요
And I'm really excited to see what people come up with.
어떤 작품이 나올지 정말 기대돼요
So that's what we got done.
그렇게 했어요
And would you believe we are already 2.5% through the course on the way to being an LLM engineering
벌써 두 살이라니 믿어지세요? 5%만 더 배우면 LLM 공학 전문가가
expert, so it's already progress has been made.
될 겁니다 이미 진전이 있었던 거죠
Tomorrow we're going to talk about what really is that journey like what are the steps.
내일은 그 여정이 뭔지 얘기할 거예요 어떤 단계인지 같은 거요
So you have a clear sense of what's what's to be done, set you up for success.
뭘 해야 할지 확실히 알고 성공하도록 준비하는 거죠
And then we'll do some, some, some content.
그리고 몇 가지 내용을 다룰 거예요
We'll talk about what are the leading frontier models and the different ways to use them.
선구적인 개척자 모델은 무엇이며 이를 활용하는 다양한 방법에 대해 얘기해 보죠
And we'll also do some quick lab work, something I promised you that people who would prefer not to
실험실 작업도 할 겁니다 오픈라이에 돈을 쓰기 싫어하는
fork out dollars to OpenAI.
사람들이 있을 거예요
I'm going to show you how we could use Olama as an alternative with the same code that we just wrote,
방금 쓴 것과 같은 코드로 Olama를 대체할 수 있는 방법을 보여드리겠습니다 Preftier
calling Olama running locally instead of calling out to the frontier model on the cloud.
모델을 클라우드에서 호출하는 대신 Olama를 로컬로 실행하는 거죠
So we'll do that tomorrow too.
내일도 그렇게 하죠
Very much looking forward to it.
정말 기대돼요
And I will see you then.
그때 봐요